CONTACT



337-230-5581



lburleigh09@gmail.com



www.betweenthelobes.com



www.linkedin.com/in/lburleigh

EXPERTISE SKILLS

Null Hypothesis Statistic Testing

Data Validation + Visualization

Machine + Transfer Learning

Bayesian Statistics

Coding Error Resolution

Data Management

Data Presentation

Problem Solving

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

Analytical + Critical Thinking

Self-motivated

Adaptable

Prioritization + Planning

Project Management

Communication

Teamwork + Collaboration

Independent Work + Progress

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Gimp Microsoft Office

Github NLP

Google G-Suite Python

HTML R

LaTex SPSS

Linux/Bash SQL

Matlab

LAURYN (L) BURLEIGH PH.D.



ABOUT ME

Expertise in gathering, cleaning, analyzing, and presenting data to technical and non-technical personnel. Advanced understanding of many statistical analyses and data presentation. Highly organized, motivated, and diligent with significant background in cognitive and computational research, collaborating with computer scientists on implementing novel machine leaning algorithms.

WORK EXPERIENCE

A/B testing in R Course Instructor - DataCamp

01/2023- Current

Creating an online course to teach data scientists and statisticians parametric and non parametric analyses, data visualization, and data presentation using R.

Graduate Researcher - Louisiana State University

08/2016 - Current

Conducted analyses on quantitative data using Frequentist Null Hypothesis Statistic Testing, Bayesian Statistics, Machine Learning, and Transfer Learning analyses after collecting, organizing, and cleaning data sets. Created and presented slides to describe analyses, findings, and limitations of studies. Wrote single and multi-experiment manuscripts for relevant journal publication, highlighting and explaining statistical analyses and results. Headed multiple research projects managing 2-8 additional researchers using self-report, skin conductance response, and fMRI measures to investigate the acquisition and generalization of fear to visually perceived and mentally imagined stimuli.

Collaborated as team member of 2-10 researchers on multiple projects investigating fear, mental rotation, working memory, and other cognitive processes, assisting in selection and implementation of statistical analyses. Provided assistance in methodology creation, instruction on measurement collection, and manuscript revision for journal publication.

Graduate Teaching Assistant - Louisiana State University **08/2019 - 12/2022**

Created and instructed labs and lectures on statistical analyses using R and SPSS to undergraduate and graduate students in General Statistics and Intermediate Statistics courses of 15-30 students. Provided an understanding and implementation of distributions, hypotheses, and Null Hypothesis Statistic Test analyses including, but not limited to, z-test, t-tests, ANOVAs, regression, correlation, Chi-square tests, effect sizes, sample sizes, and power analyses, following with data visualization, presentation, and reporting results.

Undergraduate Research Assistant - University of New Orleans

08/2013 - 12/2015

Assisted a team of 5 graduate students gathering, arranging, and maintaining research data collected using self-report, reaction time, salivation, pulse, heart rate and fMRI measures, including creation and coding of automatic calculation data forms and questionnaires and maintaining and calibrating lab equipment for studies investigating stress, cognition, and affective states in special population children with 22q11.2 deletion syndrome.

EDUCATION

M.A., PhD - Louisiana State University

08/2016 - 05/2023

Cognitive and Brain Science
PhD Dissertation: Domain Adaptation Algorithm

M.A. Thesis: Neural Mechanisms of Fear

B.S - University of New Orleans **01/2012 - 12/2014**

Psychology Cum Laude